# Vanessa Fernandez 2012 Sequoia Court Woodbridge, VA 22191 Cell: (201) 566-1710 Vfernandez@keystone.edu

#### Summary:

I am currently a Kindergarten teacher at a Title I. school in Virginia. I graduated from Keystone College with a degree in Early Childhood Education as well as Special Education. I also graduated with a double major in Psychology. I have ample experience working with children as well as having a vast knowledge of information relating to children, how they learn, and how they develop. I am committed to helping children learn and achieve to the best of their abilities.

# Highlights:

- -Calm and Patient
- -6 + years of experience working with children
- -Cooperative team member
- -Attentive to detail
- -Quick learner
- -Instructional I. Pennsylvania Certification
- -Computer proficient
- -Hard working and dedicated
- -Well organized
- -First Aid and CPR Certified
- -Act 126 Certification

# **Accomplishments:**

- -Managed classes of up to 21 students
- -Designed lesson plans focused on age and level appropriate material
- -Guided student learning in large groups as well as small groups
- -Planned and conducted educational activities that provided students with opportunities to observe, question, and investigate
- -Conducted observations as well as various forms of assessment on students

#### Experience:

### **Bel Air Elementary School**

**November 2016 to Present** 

# **EEC SACC Teacher**

# Woodbridge, VA

- -Promoted learning and discovery through hands on activities
- -Chose books and setup weekly read alouds for grades K-2
- -Created weekly activities based on Virginia's Standards of Learning (SOL) for grades K-5
- -Established safe play environments for the children
- -Developed rapport with students

#### **Bel Air Elementary School**

**August 2016 to Present** 

# Kindergarten Teacher

# Woodbridge, VA

- -Promoted learning and discovery through hands on activities
- -Promoted good behavior by using positive reinforcement methods as well as a behavioral chart system
- -Created weekly lesson plans based on Virginia's Standards of Learning (SOL)
- -Established safe play environments for the children
- -Developed professional relationships with parents and families

#### **Greater Carbondale YMCA**

September 2015 to August 2016

# Early Head-Start Older Toddler Teacher

#### Carbondale, PA

- -Maintained daily records of children's individual activities, behaviors, meals and naps
- -Promoted good behaviors by using positive reinforcement methods
- -Established a safe play environment for children
- -Encouraged children to be understanding of one another
- -Created age and developmentally appropriate lessons, themes and activities for children
- -Established a good rapport with children as well as their families

Education:
Keystone College

Bachelor of Science: Early Childhood and Special Education

La Plume, PA, United States

- -Double major in Psychology
- -Coursework in Behavior Management as well as Classroom Management

2015

- -Coursework in Child Development, Autism and Learning Disabilities -Coursework in Family, School, and Community cooperation